beautyoftheweb.com 2015-05-31

# Microsoft.com Privacy Statement

Microsoft.com Privacy Statement 

This privacy statement applies to Microsoft.com and Microsoft websites, services and products that collect data and display these terms, as well as their offline product support services. It does not apply to Microsoft sites, services and products that do not display or link to this statement or that have their own privacy statements. 

Please read the summaries below and click on "Learn More" for more details on a particular topic. You may also select from the products listed above to view that product's privacy statement. Some products, services or features mentioned in this statement may not be available in all markets. You can find more information on Microsoft's commitment to protecting your privacy at <http://www.microsoft.com/privacy>. 

Cookies & Similar TechnologiesCookies

Most Microsoft websites use "cookies," which are small text files stored on your device, to help operate the sites and collect information about online activity. For instance, we use cookies to store your preferences and settings; help with sign-in; provide targeted ads; combat fraud; and analyze site operations. 

We also use web beacons to help deliver cookies and compile analytics. These may include web beacons from third-party service providers.

You have a variety of tools to control cookies and similar technologies, including:

  * Browser controls to block and delete cookies; 
  * Advertising controls, including Microsoft's controls at <http://choice.live.com/advertisementchoice/>, to opt out of receiving behaviorally targeted ads; and 
  * Controls from some analytics service providers to opt out of data collection through web beacons. 

Information We CollectCollecting Your Information

Microsoft collects many kinds of information in order to operate effectively and provide you the best products, services and experiences we can.

We collect information when you register, sign in and use our sites and services. We also may get information from other companies.

We collect this information in a variety of ways, including from web forms, technologies like [cookies](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/EN-US/Core/default.aspx?componentid=pspCookiesModule&view=Description "cookies"), web logging and software on your computer or other device. 

How We Use Your Personal InformationUsing Your Information

Microsoft uses the information we collect to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer.

We also may use the information to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account and security updates.

And we may use the information to help make the ads you see on our ad-supported services more relevant.

Reasons We Share Your Personal InformationSharing Your Information

We will share your personal information with your consent.  We may also share or disclose information with Microsoft affiliates and vendors; when required by law or to respond to legal process; to protect our customers; to protect lives; to maintain the security of our services; and to protect the rights or property of Microsoft.

Accessing Your Personal InformationAccessing Your Information

Some Microsoft services give you the ability to view or edit your personal information online. To help prevent others from viewing your personal information, you first will be required to sign in. How you can access your personal information will depend on which sites or services you have used.

ChildrenChildren

When a Microsoft site or service collects age information, it will block users under 13 or obtain consent from a parent or guardian before their child can use it. 

When consent is granted, the child's account is treated much like any other account, including letting the account holder communicate with other users.

Parents can change or revoke consent as described in this privacy statement.

Display of AdvertisingAdvertising

Most of the online advertisements on Microsoft sites and services are displayed by Microsoft Advertising. When we display online advertisements to you, we will place one or more [cookies](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/EN-US/Core/default.aspx?componentid=pspCookiesModule&view=Description) in order to recognize your computer when we display an ad to you. Over time, we may gather information from the sites where we serve ads and use the information to help provide more relevant ads. 

**You may opt out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting our**[ **opt-out page**](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759) **.**

Communication PreferencesCommunications

You can stop the delivery of future promotional email from Microsoft sites and services by following the specific instructions in the email you receive. Depending on the respective service, you may also have the option of proactively making choices about the receipt of promotional email, telephone calls, and postal mail for particular Microsoft sites or services.

Location Based ServicesLocation Based Services

Certain services or features can use information about your location to provide services you request or personalize your experience.  Location information may include data identifying nearby cell towers and Wi-Fi hotspots, as wells as Global Position System (GPS) data.  For more information about location based services, please click on “Learn More.”

Support DataSupport Data

Support Data is the information we collect when you submit a support request or run an automated troubleshooter, including information about hardware, software, and other details related to the support incident, such as: contact or authentication information, chat session personalization, information about the condition of the machine and the application from when the fault occurred and during diagnostics, system and registry data about software installations and hardware configurations, and error-tracking files. We use Support Data as described in this privacy statement, and additionally use it to resolve your support incident and for training purposes.

Payment DataPayment Data

Payment Data is the information that you provide when you make online purchases. This may include your payment instrument number ( _e.g.,_ credit card, PayPal), your name and billing address, and the security code associated with your payment instrument ( _e.g.,_ the CSV or CVV). This section provides additional information regarding the collection and use of your payment information.

Microsoft accountMicrosoft account

Microsoft account is a service that lets you sign in to Microsoft products, web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners. When you create a Microsoft account, we ask you to provide certain information. When you sign in to a site or service using your Microsoft account, we collect certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious account usage and to protect the efficiency and security of the Microsoft account service.  We also send some of this information to sites and services that you sign in to with your Microsoft account.

We use demographic information – gender, country, age and postal code but not your name or contact information – from your Microsoft account to provide personalized ads to you. **You may opt out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting our** **[ **opt-out page**](https://choice.live.com/AdvertisementChoice/). **

To view additional details about Microsoft account, including how to create and use a Microsoft account, how to edit account information, and how we collect and use information relating to a Microsoft account, please click on Learn More.

Other Important Privacy InformationOther Information

 **Learn more about**

  * Protecting the security of personal information 
  * Where we store and process information 
  * Changes to our privacy statements 

**How to Contact Us**

  * If you have a technical or general support question, please visit <http://support.microsoft.com/> to learn more about Microsoft Support offerings. 
  * If you have a Microsoft account password question, please visit [Microsoft account support.](http://go.microsoft.com/FWLink/p/?LinkID=320207)
  * If you have a general privacy question or a question for the Chief Privacy Officer of Microsoft or want to request access to your personal information, please contact us by using our [Web form](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=321116 "Web form"). 
    * By mail: Microsoft Privacy, Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, Washington 98052 USA 
    * By Phone: 425-882-8080
  * Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited is our data protection representative for the European Economic Area and Switzerland. The data protection officer of Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited can be reached at the following address:

> Microsoft Ireland Operations, Ltd.  
>  Attn: Data Protection  
>  Carmenhall Road  
>  Sandyford, Dublin 18, Ireland

  * To find the Microsoft subsidiary in your country or region, see <http://www.microsoft.com/worldwide/>.
